* [ ] Search

Toggle navigation

    Why VSL
    
    At Voyager Sopris Learning®, our mission is to work with educators to help them meet and surpass their goals for student achievement.

    Solutions

    Overview
    
    Training and Support by Product
    
    We work with schools and districts to customize an implementation and ongoing support plan.

Privacy Policy & Terms of Use
=============================

* Terms and Conditions

**Privacy Statement for Voyager Sopris Learning, Inc. Data Management System**
------------------------------------------------------------------------------

This site provides you with access to Voyager Sopris' Data Management System. This system is an integral component of Voyager Sopris' curriculum products and provides valuable reporting, instructional recommendations, and other resources used by teachers and other instructional leaders in conjunction with Voyager Sopris' curriculum with the goal of improving student performance.

This statement describes the privacy and security practices Voyager Sopris employs for this site. We have adopted these practices to protect you, the students, and the school district, and to enable each of us to comply with applicable legal requirements. Use of this site requires district acceptance of the practices outlined in this statement.

Two types of personally identifiable information are used on this site: **your personal data** and **student data**.

**Your Personal Data**  
_Collection_: Voyager Sopris collects information from you as you use this site. For example, you must enter certain personally identifiable information, including your name, e-mail address, and phone number. We use this information to verify your identity and prevent unauthorized access to your account and to contact you in connection with your use of this site.

In addition to the information you provide, Voyager Sopris collects information about your use of this site through tracking, cookies, and log files, as described in our general [Terms of Use](#terms) statement. 

_Protection_: Because you enter your personal data, you control its accuracy. If you discover that your personal data is inaccurate or if it changes, you may make corrections by notifying us at [support@voyagersopris.com](mailto:support@voyagersopris.com) or 888-399-1995. We will not share your personal data collected through this site with third persons without your consent. However, your personal data will be available to authorized users from your school district who have permission from the school district to access it. We will not use your personal data collected through this site for any purpose other than providing you with access to this site and the associated services. We will use the same security to protect your personal data that we use to protect student data collected through this site.

**Student Data**  
As you use this site, you will enter student data or interact with student data that has already been entered. Federal law (the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act, "FERPA") allows a school district to release student records to an organization that is "conducting studies for, or on behalf of, educational agencies or institutions for the purpose of developing, validating, or administering predictive tests... \[or\] improving instruction."

However, FERPA requires limitations on disclosure of those records and implementation of appropriate security measures to protect those records. To help your school district comply with FERPA, Voyager Sopris has adopted certain practices, and requires that educators using this site fulfill certain responsibilities to safeguard student data. The following statement explains our practices and your responsibilities regarding the student data you enter on this site.

Additionally, Voyager Sopris operates in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”). Voyager Sopris will not knowingly collect or use personally identifiable information from anyone under 13 years of age.

**Student Data Security and Confidentiality Statement**  
_Purposes of Data Entry_: You control what student data is entered on this site. Student data entered on this site should be limited to information that is relevant to the legitimate educational purpose of improving student performance. We will not ask you to enter, and you are instructed not to enter, data about students that is not relevant to this legitimate educational purpose.

Therefore, only a minimum amount of personally identifiable student data required for the setup of the system is requested. We require student first name, student last name, and student identification number. Additional data, not specific to the student, is also required to complete system setup, including the teacher first and last name, class name, grade level, and school name. Student demographic data, for the purposes of optional disaggregated reporting, is requested separately from the initial setup data and is obtained only with written permission from your district.

Use, Disclosure, and Storage: We will use the student data to provide the services to your school district. We will not keep the student data after you or the school district instructs us to delete it. You may not disclose or otherwise use the student data entered on this site for any unauthorized purposes.

We will only disclose student data to authorized employees or representatives of the school district, and will not knowingly disclose the student data to any third person without express written authorization. When, at the request of the district, we acquire assessment or other information, including personally identifiable student data, from a third party source we treat that information with the same confidentiality and security safeguards as though it were provided directly by the district. Additional agreements may be required by the third party to authorize transmission of data to Voyager Sopris.

Your district may from time to time request that Voyager Sopris provide student data to third parties of its choosing. We will do so with written authorization, which acknowledges that Voyager Sopris is providing that data as your district's agent and that once the data is received by the third party, Voyager Sopris no longer has any control over the use or disposition of the data.

We may also use aggregated data in our research, product development, and marketing. That aggregated, non-personally identifiable data (e.g., summary or statistical data) may be shared with third parties. However, we do not use personally identifiable student data to market any products or services directly to students or their parents.

In the event that Voyager Sopris wishes, from time to time, to release aggregated data that identifies your school or school district by name, Voyager Sopris will enter into a separate agreement with you to authorize release and publication.

_Data Quality_: You are responsible for keeping the student data that you enter accurate, complete and up-to-date. If you recognize that student data is inaccurate, incomplete, or out-of-date, you are responsible for correcting it. If you experience problems making corrections to student data, please notify us at [support@voyagersopris.com](mailto:support@voyagersopris.com) or 888-399-1995 and we will assist you with making corrections.

_Security Safeguards_: We are committed to protecting student data against unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification or disclosure. Protecting student data requires efforts from us and from you. We will implement reasonable and appropriate safeguards when collecting student data from you and when storing that student data in our database and you will observe our security safeguards and exercise reasonable caution when using this site.

Specific institutional and technological security safeguards include:

1. Only Voyager Sopris employees who are authorized to handle student data are able to access the Data Management System.
2. Only school district employees and representatives that the district authorizes as school officials are permitted to access the system. It has a hierarchical permissions system.  
    This means:

1. A teacher will only be able to see data for his/her class.
2. A Principal, Coach, or other authorized School User will be able to view all data at a given school.
3. An authorized district-level employee, such as an Instructional Coordinator or Superintendent, will be able to see all data across the district.

4. Each authorized school official is given a Userid and Password valid only for the duration of the academic year, including a summer program if applicable. You must safeguard your Userid and Password, and not permit any unauthorized access to student data entered or kept in Voyager Sopris' system.
5. Upon written request by the district, Voyager Sopris will destroy any student data for districts who no longer participate in a Voyager Sopris reading program. Voyager Sopris will provide written verification that the data has been destroyed as requested.
6. If a district has not used any Voyager Sopris product for a period of ten years, Voyager Sopris will provide written notice that the student data pertaining to their district will be destroyed, unless the district requests the records be kept. Upon destruction, Voyager Sopris will provide written verification that the data has been destroyed.
7. Voyager Sopris uses industry standard server and network hardware and software to ensure that data is protected from unauthorized access or disclosure.

When you use this site, you consent to our privacy practices and agree to accept the responsibilities outlined in this statement.

### Terms of Use

**User Responsibility**

By using this web site, you are agreeing to be bound by these Terms and Conditions of Use, all applicable laws and regulations, and agree that you are responsible for compliance with any applicable local laws. If you do not agree with any of these terms, you are prohibited from using or accessing this site. All Users are responsible at all times for their use of the Voyager Sopris Learning Web Site. Voyager Sopris assumes no liability regarding any use of the Web Site by any person. At any time, and in its sole discretion, Voyager Sopris may terminate, limit, or modify access of any person to the Web Site.

**Educational Use Only**

Each User agrees to access the Web Site and to use the Services provided by Voyager Sopris only for educational purposes, and for no commercial purposes whatsoever.

**No Interruption**

Users shall not attempt to disrupt or interrupt the operation of the Web Site. Users shall not use the Web Site in any manner that could damage, impair, or interfere with any person's use of, the Web Site.

**Connection Charges**

Users are responsible for all charges associated with connecting to the Web Site.

**Public Communications and Email**

Voyager Sopris may provide certain Users the facility for posting communications in the form of e-mail, web pages, or other similar communication. Such postings are intended for public consumption and the author shall have no expectation of privacy in such communications. Such communications may not contain offensive material as defined herein. Users may post only their original work. Voyager Sopris will not be responsible for the content of materials posted by Users, and does not attempt to review all communications made to or through the Web Site. Voyager Sopris retains the right, but has no obligation, to monitor such postings, either randomly or in response to inquiries, or both, in order to detect and remove any material that Voyager Sopris, in its sole discretion, believes to be offensive, obscene, slanderous, or in any way contrary to law or to Voyager Sopris policies. In posting any communications, the User grants to Voyager Sopris a fully-paid, perpetual, worldwide, and royalty-free right to copy, display, and distribute and such communications in such form and manner as Voyager Sopris in its sole discretion may deem beneficial to its subscribers.

“Offensive Material” includes, but is not limited to, material that:

* Is obscene, offensive, indecent, pornographic, sexually explicit or abusive;
* Contains any racial, religious, or ethnic insult;
* Contains false or misleading statements of fact;
* Constitutes impersonation of another person;
* Is slanderous, libelous or defames any person or entity;
* Causes injury to any person or entity;
* Infringes the privacy or intellectual property rights of any person or entity;
* Is contrary to law or to public policy;
* In any way violates this Agreement or any Voyager Sopris policy;
* Includes any survey, contest, pyramid scheme, or chain letter;
* Advertises or offers to sell or buy any goods or services for any commercial purpose;
* Collects or harvests information about others without their express consent;
* Solicits funds, except for the benefit of Customer and for a charitable or educational purpose;
* Or contains any software virus or other code or routine designed to interrupt, destroy, or limit the functionality of any computer.

**  
Links**

Voyager Sopris may on its Web Site provide hyperlinks and pointers to other sites on the Internet maintained by third parties. Such links do not constitute an endorsement by Voyager Sopris. Voyager Sopris and its affiliates are not responsible for the content, availability, accuracy, or currency of other sites. No person may link to www.voyagersopris.com without the express permission of Voyager Sopris.

**Copyrights**

Voyager Sopris and its Licensors are the owners of all content and materials on the Web Site, which is protected by copyright and other laws. Users may, on an occasional and irregular basis, disseminate an insubstantial portion of the content from the Web Site, for any non-commercial purpose, without charge, and may transmit the same, in tangible non-electronic form only, to a limited number of individuals. In transmitting any such material, Users must include all copyright and other proprietary right information unchanged in form, must include original source attribution, and must include the phrase "Used with the Permission of Voyager Sopris, Inc." Users may not post any content of the Voyager Sopris Web Site to any newsgroup, mail list or electronic bulletin board. Users may not reproduce, transmit, sell, distribute, or in any way exploit the Web Site or any portion thereof for any commercial use.

**Limitation of Liability / No Warranty**

Voyager Sopris Learning, its employees, and its authors make no representations, and assume no liability, legal or otherwise, for the accuracy, reliability, applicability, use, or misuse of the information and strategies described on this website or in its publications. All functionalities are provided “as is”, and without warranties of any kind, express or implied. **_To the fullest extent permitted by law, Voyager Sopris expressly disclaims any warranty of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, and moreover disclaims any warranty of title, compatibility, security, accuracy, and non-infringement._** The content provided may include facts, views, opinions and recommendations of persons other than Voyager Sopris, which are deemed by Voyager Sopris to be of interest to Users. Neither Voyager Sopris nor its Licensors guarantee or warrant the accuracy, completeness, or timeliness of such content, or otherwise endorse the authors. Voyager Sopris intends no portion of the content as professional advice, particularly with regard to determining and implementing the best course of action for an individual student.

**General**

This Policy sets forth the entire understanding and agreement between the parties with respect to the subject matter hereof.

**Modification**

We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time by posting an amended Policy that is always accessible on this site’s home page and by giving you prior notice of such amendments. Your continued use of this Website after a modification indicates your acceptance of the amended Policy.

**Governing Law & Venue**

Any claim relating to the Voyager Sopris web site shall be governed by the laws of the State of Texas without regard to its conflict of law provisions. Any dispute will be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts located within Dallas County in the State of Texas, and User hereby submits to the personal jurisdiction of such courts.

**Indemnity**

Users agree to indemnify and hold Voyager Sopris and (as applicable) Voyager Sopris’s parent, subsidiaries, owners, affiliates, officers, directors, consultants, suppliers, agents and employees harmless from any claim or demand, including reasonable attorneys; fees, made by any third party due to or arising out of your breach of the Terms and Conditions, or your violation of any law or the rights of a third party.

**Severability**

If any part of these Terms of Use / Privacy Policy is held to be unenforceable, such holding shall not affect the validity of the other provisions of the Terms of Use, which shall remain in full force and effect.

**Survival**

The following Sections survive any termination or expiration of this Agreement: No Warranty, Severability, Indemnity, Governing Law.

### Still have questions?

If you have any questions about this terms of use and privacy statement, please contact: [customerservice@cambiumlearning.com](mailto:customerservice@cambiumlearning.com).  
  
Note: Any updated policies will be posted to the service immediately.

Company

Need Help?

If you are interested in learning more about our solutions.

For technical support, training, or have a general question.

Let's Connect

Monday through Friday  
8:00 a.m.–5:30 p.m.  
Central Time

© Copyright 2024 Lexia Voyager Sopris [Privacy Policy](https://www.voyagersopris.com/terms-conditions)

A [Cambium Learning](https://cambiumlearning.com/)® Group Brand [](https://cambiumlearning.com/)
